Guide to the Picture File, 1600s-1979 and undated, bulk 1814-1950
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Oversize Materials Not in Main Collection
  - People Series
    - "The Right Hon. William Wyndham Grenville," 1815, (black-and-white engraving) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
    - Lincoln, Abraham, 1908, (black-and-white etching) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      Etching by Max Rosenthal.
    - "Commander in Chief of the Grand Army of the Republic," 1885, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
    - Johnson, Andrew, undated, (black-and-white lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
    - U.S. House of Representatives, 1860, (black-and-white photo) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
    - General Grant and his family, 1866, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
    - Abraham Lincoln, Frederick Douglas, and Booker T. Washington, undated, (2 black-and-white lithographs (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
    - George Washington, Abraham Licoln, "Columbia's noblest sons," 1865, (black-and-white lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
  - Subjects Series
    - Civil War
      - "Bombardment and Capture of Fredericksburg, VA," 1862, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
        Currier and Ives.
      - "The Brave Wife," undated, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - "Respectfully Inscribed to the crew of the Kearsarge, Commodore Winslows Grand Victory March," 1864, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - Major General Ambrise E. Burnside, undated, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - Military Register for Company H, 20th Regiment Pennsylvania volunteer Cavalry, undated, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - The Army of the Potomac, 1863, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - View of Transparency in front of Headquarters of Supervisory committee for recruiting colored Regiments, Chestnut Street, PA., 1864, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - Inauguration of Jefferson Davis, 1878, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - Fort Federal Hill, Baltimore MD, 1862, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - Jarvis U.S. General Hospital, Baltimore MD, 1864, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - The US Monitor "Weehawken" and the U.S. Steam Sloop "Iroquois" in a gale of wind off Chincoteague shoals, Va., 1864, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - Girl giving Confederate officer directions, 1893, (black-and-white illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - "Home on a Furlough," 1864, (black-and-white engraving) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - Camp Washburn, 10th Maine Regiment, Col. George L. Beal, 1861, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - "In Commemoration of the glorious victories of the 3rd an 9th of April 1864, Richmond Virginia," undated, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - The Army of the Potomac, 1863, (color lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
      - "General Sherman On the March to the Sea," 1868, (black-and-white engraving) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
    - Miscellaneous
      - "The Protecting Angel," 1910, (black-and-white lithograph) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
        Depicts white angel keeping two African American children from falling off a cliff.
      - War Bonds Poster, undated, (color illustration) (Opaperfolder OC:IV:15)
        Preservation issues.
  - Currier and Ives Lithographs
    Framed and in color unless noted otherwise. Source currently unidentified.
    - The Little Volunteer, (young female child in military costume), 1862, (lithograph) (Box CUR1)
    - Battle of Mill Spring, Ky., Jan. 19th 1862, circa 1863, (lithograph) (Box CUR1)
    - The Night After the Battle, 1863, (lithograph) (Box CUR1)
    - The Soldiers Home, The Vision, 1862, (lithograph) (Box CUR2)
      Includes two-stanza poem.
    - Death of General Lyon, 1862, (lithograph) (Box CUR2)
      Subtitle indicates Battle of Wilsons Creek, Missouri, 1861 Aug. 10
    - The Soldier Boy, 'On Duty', 1864, (lithograph) (Box CUR2)
    - South Carolina's 'Ultimatum', circa 1861, (lithograph) (Box CUR3)
      Black and white political cartoon featuring President Buchanan, Fort Sumter, and Governor Pickens. Unframed.
    - The Tomb of Washington. Mount Vernon Va., undated, (lithograph) (Box CUR3)
      Unframed.
    - General Philip Kearney, circa 1863, (lithograph) (Box CUR3)
    - Major Genl. John Pope. Commanding U.S. Army of Virginia, circa 1862, (lithograph) (Box CUR3)
      Promoted to Commander of the Army of Virginia in March 1862, Pope was dismissed from this command in September 1862. Unframed.
    - Major Genl. John C. Fremont. U.S. Army, undated, (lithograph) (Box CUR3)
    - The Sunny South, 1870, (lithograph) (Box CUR3)
    - The Bombardment and Capture of Fort Fisher, N.C. Jny. 15th 1865, circa 1865, (lithograph) (Box CUR3)
    - The Capture of Atlanta, Georgia, Sept. 2d. 1864, circa 1864, (lithograph) (Box CUR3)
    - The Battle of New Bern, N.C. March 14th 1862, 1862, (lithograph) (Box CUR3)
    - The Lexington of 1861, circa 1862, (lithograph) (Box CUR4)
      Subtitle indicates battle of 1861 Apr. 19, Baltimore.
    - The Victory of Roanoke, Fby. 8th 1862, circa 1862, (lithograph) (Box CUR4)
      Featuring the charge of the New York 9th Zouaves.